Zack, Arnold Arbitration Files 6141
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Arnold Zack Arbitration Files
1993-2005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Zack, Arnold
6141
15 cubic feet
15 linear ft.
Records.
5819044
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 12, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Lawyer, arbitrator, and government official; LLB Yale, 1956, MBA Harvard, 1961, MA Harvard, 1963.
Arnold Marshall Zack is an arbitrator and mediator. Beginning his labor career as a part-time election examiner for the National Labor Relations Board and as a case analyst for the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board (1950-1953), he was also a lecturer in labor economics at Simmons College, Northeastern University (1957-1963); an assistant to Saul Wallen, arbitrator, (1956-1960); director of the Labor-Management Institute of the American Academy of Arbitrators (1966-1968); and has served in various labor-related international posts for the United States government.
Other governmental service includes membership on panels for the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, the Massachusetts Public Employment Relations Board, the New York State Public Employment Relations Board, The New Jersey Public Employment Relations Board, The New York City Office of Collective Bargaining, and The National Mediation Board. Zack is also a panel member of the American Arbitration Association, and has served as the permanent arbitrator for a number of major corporations and unions and for the State of New York and the U.S. Postal Service.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5281: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5512: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5551: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5620: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5659: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5727: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5786: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5825: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5861: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5913: Arnold Zack Additional Aarbitration Files 5950: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Cases 5979: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 6049: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Cases 6066: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 6104: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 6250: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions; Government employee unions; Fire fighters -- Labor unions; Police -- Labor unions; Teachers' unions; Arbitration, Industrial; Collective bargaining; Airlines -- Employees -- Labor unions; Waltham (Mass.) -- Labor unions; Bossi, Ruthane; Zack, Arnold.; ABC, Inc. --Archives; International Association of Fire Fighters --Archives; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians --Archives; National Treasury Employees Union --Archives; Union Pacific Railroad Company --Archives; United States. Internal Revenue Service--Archives; United States. National Mediation Board--Archives
5819044
- American Broadcasting Company and National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Broadcasting Company and National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Town of Arlington Police Department, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Town of Barrington, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes 2 videos
- Town of Billerica and Service Employees International Union, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Town of Billerica: Termination, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Town of Billerica: Termination, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bridgeport Police Commission Inquiry, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Business Express Flight Attendants, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Clarkstown Teachers, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts and Massachusetts Correction Officers Federated Union, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- East Bridgewater Education Association, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Town of Falmouth and Fire Fighters, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- City of Manchester and Fire Fighters, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Metropolitan Museum of Art, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Miller Company and PACE, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- National Mediation Board and Union Pacific Rail Road, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- National Mediation Board and Union Pacific Rail Road, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Park Avenue Cement Block, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Plymouth City Sheriff Department, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Shaws Supermarkets and United Food and Commercial Workers, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- United States Customs and National Treasury Employees Union, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- XPEDX and International Paper and International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 504, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Air Tran Airways and National Pilots' Association, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- American Red Cross and American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Bay State Gas Company and Utility Workers' Union of America, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Bell Atlantic/Verizon/NYNEX and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- City of Boston and the National Association of Government Employees/International Brotherhood of Police Officers, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bristol County Sheriff's Office and Massachusetts Correction Officers Federated Union, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Einstein College and 1199, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Gate Gourmet and International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hartford Board of Education and Hartford Federation of Teachers, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 1999-2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts and Massachusetts Correction Officers Federated Union, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- State of New Hampshire and State Employees Association of New Hampshire/Service Employees International Union, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Otis Elevator and International Union of Elevator Constructors, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Providence Journal Company and Providence Newspaper Guild, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- City of Waltham and International Association of Firefighters, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- City of Waltham and International Association of Fire Fighters, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Town of Westborough and International Brotherhood of Police Officers, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Chelmsford and International Brotherhood of Police Officers, Local 341, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  March 4, 2003.
- Danaher Tool, Incorporated, and International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers - Communications Workers of America, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  March 20, 2003
- City of East Providence and United Steelworkers of America, Local 15509, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  November 12, 2003
- Town of Hudson and International Brotherhood of Police Officers, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  December 18, 2002.
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  September 26, 2002- October 1, 2003.
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  March 13, 2003-June 9, 2003.
- Shaws and United Food and Commercial Workers Local 791, 2001-2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  December 5, 2001-October 2, 2003
- Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees and Federation of Union Representatives, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  November 4, 2003
- Air Tran and Association of Flight Attendants, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  August 9, 2004
- Bristol County and Massachusetts Correction Officers Federated Union, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  January 13, 2004
- Town of Bellingham and International Association of Fire Fighters, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  December 1, 2003.
- Chicopee and United Food and Commercial Workers Local 1459, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  May 6, 2004
- City Market and United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America Local 203, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  March 24, 2004
- East Haven Educational Association and Board of Education, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  January 21, 2004
- Haverhill Paperboard Company and PACE, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  December 3, 2003
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  April 13, 2004
- Internal Revenue Service and National Treasury Employees Union, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Mansfield, Massachusetts, and Police, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  September 21, 2004
- New Hampshire State and Service Employees International Union Local 1984, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  April 22, 2004; October 1, 2004.
- Shaws and United Food and Commercial Workers, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  March 2, 2004; March 20, 2004; June 8, 2004; November 16, 2004.
- UNICCO and Service Employees International Union Local 615, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  October 14, 2004
- West Warwick, Rhode Island and International Brotherhood of Police Officers Local 312, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  September 27, 2004
- Warwick, Rhode Island and Fraternal Order of Police Lodge 7, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  February 4, 2004
- WGBH and National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  December 5, 2003; December 22, 2003; January 16, 2004
- New England Gas and Utility Workers Union of America, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  October 20, 2004
- Central Maine Power Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  March 8, 2005; April 6, 2005.
- Commonwealth of Massachusetts/Massachusetts Nurses Association, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  May 2, 2005
- Family Service of Greater Boston/Service Employees International Union, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  June 16, 2005; October 5, 2005.
- Holyoke Gas, Limited and Power/Gas and Electric Department, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  December 14, 2004
- International Playing Card/Graphics, Teamster Interest Arbitration, 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  December 15, 2003; December 16, 2003; January 4, 2004
- Internal Revenue Service/National Treasury Employees Union, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  June 14, 2005; April 22, 2005
- Narrangasett Electric Company (National Grid)/Brotherhood of Utility Workers, Local 310, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  April 25, 2005
- Naval Undersea Warfare/Federal Union of Scientists and Engineers 144, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  November 2, 2005
- Shaw's/United Food and Commercial Workers, 2004-2005 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  May 11, 2004; October 28, 2004; November 8, 2004; March 28, 2005; March 31, 2005; April 19, 2005; May 10, 2005; June 1, 2005; June 2, 2005; June 13, 2005; June 15, 2005.
- United States Customs/National Treasury Employees Union, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  June 8, 2005; September 14, 2005.
- United States Customs/National Treasury Employees Union, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Veterans Affairs Boston Health Care/American Federation of Government Employees Local 2143, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  November 22, 2004
- Vanderbilt Chemical/PACE, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  October 6, 2005
- Verizon/International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers 2323, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  April 20, 2005